<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>BaoLong (Posts about golang)</title><link>https://baolonglin.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" href="https://baolonglin.github.io/categories/golang.xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:lbl52001@gmail.com"&gt;Baolong Lin&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 21:43:19 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Try golang</title><link>https://baolonglin.github.io/posts/try-golang/</link><dc:creator>Baolong Lin</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Recently read one short book &lt;b&gt;The Little Go Book&lt;/b&gt; by Karl Seguin.
It makes me want to try it a little bit, write small tools
with static link and lot build in libraries.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There is one small tool which was written by C++, it uses
boost, mongocxx, libcrafter, libpcap, pthread, bsoncxx, bz2, etc.
I was really paid a lot time to prepare them, because my
work environment does not have many libraries installed, and I have
no root permission, what a bad situation, I need to compile
them, maintain them under my own directory.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The tool is quite simple, one feature is parsing the pcap file, or extract
the pcap file from tar, compressed tar, collect the all sip
message inside the pcap file, do a little bit process,
 store them into mongodb. Another feature is parse TTCN
source code with antlr, collect information based on the
AST.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Fully rewrite it only cost me several days with spare time,
ipdefrag cost me time to read the APIs, the others are quite
straight forward. It's only 403 line with comments, blank line
and curly blanket, and some duplicate code which i don't have
time to remove them. It's amazing, for my limit work
environment, just solved a small compilation issue that
libpcap version is too low in that environment, less
than the C++ version.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Have feeling that for small tools, golang becomes one of my
options to achieve them, even I am not so familiar with it.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>golang</category><guid>https://baolonglin.github.io/posts/try-golang/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 14:28:26 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>